Kristopher Kurzawa

248-568-2806 kurzawa1@yahoo.com 243 Pare St. Clawson MI 48017 United States

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/kris-kurzawa-34105226b

GitHub: https://github.com/KKurzawa

Portfolio: https://kkurzawa.github.io/KrisKurzawa-Portfolio/

Profile

I am a full-stack web developer with demonstrated experience across the software development life cycle with an emphasis in JavaScript as my primary object oriented language. I am a lifelong musician/music educator who has performed all over the world and is currently on faculty at Wayne State University's jazz department.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Web APIs, jQuery, Bootstrap, Server-Side APIs, Bulma, OOP, Express.js, Node.js, MySql, ORM, MVC, Computer Science, NoSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, PWA, REACT, MERN, JSON

Projects

Movie Project | https://github.com/KKurzawa/Movie-Project | https://kkurzawa.github.io/Movie-Project/

- Summary: This project creates a movie database that allows users to search for a movie, give the
 user options based on their search and trending options, then displays the poster, cast, and
 storyline of their selection along with similar movies.
- Role: Front end developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bulma, TMBD API

Grocery Store Management System |

https://github.com/KKurzawa/Grocery-Store-Employee-Management-System | https://secure-gorge-43395-b510f5266de9.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: This employee management system allows users to see their role, sick/vacations
 hours, schedule for the week, a graph of hours worked in the previous week, and the ability to
 clock in and out.
- Role: Front end developer
- Tools: Node.js, Javascript, MySQL, CSS, Heroku, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Express, Sequalize, Apex Charts, Bcrypt, JawsDB

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/KKurzawa/Weather-Dashboard | https://kkurzawa.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- Summary: A weather dashboard that displays today's weather and the forecast for the next 5
 days of the entered city.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, OpenweathermapAPI, Bootstrap

Experience

ADJUNCT FACULTY, WAYNE STATE UNIVERSITY; DETROIT, MI - 2018 - PRESENT;

- Taught private jazz guitar lessons to students of varying levels of ability to grow their technique, expand their repertoire, understand music theory, and apply theory to their instrument.
- Ran a guitar ensemble consisting of 5 guitarists, a pianist, bassist, and drummer. Ensemble
 rehearsals focused on strengthening sight reading and ensemble playing by working through
 arrangements that would be polished and performed at the end of the semester.

HEAD OF GUITAR DEPARTMENT, DETROIT INSTITUTE OF MUSIC EDUCATION; DETROIT, MI - 2014 -2021;

- Taught classes focusing on guitar technique of varying styles, sight reading, music theory and applying theory to the guitar.
- Managed the other guitar instructors and coordinated with the other heads of department to facilitate a healthy and productive learning environment.

MUSICIAN, SELF EMPLOYED; DETROIT, MI - 2003 - PRESENT;

- Performances in all genres of music at multiple types of venues including festivals, studios, music venues, theaters, and broadway musicals.
- Released 3 full length albums.
- Nominated for 18 Detroit Music Awards. Awarded 7 Detroit Music Awards.

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp - Michigan State University; East Lansing, MI - 2023

Masters in Music, Jazz Studies - Wayne State University; Detroit - 2012 Bachelors in Music, Jazz Studies - Wayne State University; Detroit - 2003

Awards

2023 Outstanding Tribute Band - Detroit Music Awards

2017 Outstanding Jazz Composer - Detroit Music Awards

2016 Outstanding Jazz Recording - Detroit Music Awards

2016 Outstanding Modern Jazz Artist/Group - Detroit Music Awards

2015 Outstanding World Artist/Group - Detroit Music Awards

2015 Outstanding World/Reggae Songwriter - Detroit Music Awards

2011 Outstanding World/Reggae Songwriter - Detroit Music Awards

Talent Scholarship - Wayne State University - 2009

Evangeline Dumesnil Scholarship - Wayne State University - 2010